

### Skills

Top 1% Contributor on Stack Overflow
Exceptional Achievements in the
Programming Community

### C# Development (Expert)

Web, Desktop, Server, and Mobile Applications

### JavaScript / TypeScript (Expert)

Web, Desktop, and Mobile Applications (React, Vue, Angular, Svelte)

### APIs (Expert)

GraphQL & REST APIs

### **SQL Databases (Proficient)**

PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MariaDB, MySQL, SQLite

### NoSQL Databases (Proficient) MongoDB, Firebase, Redis

Serverless (Proficient)

### AWS Lambda, Google Cloud Functions,

Azure Functions

Edge Computing (Competent)

## DevOps (Competent)

Docker, Kubernetes, GitHub Actions, GitLab

Edge Functions & Edge Runtime

## Spoken Languages

German (native)

## English (B2)

### **Denis Knaack**

Software Development & Consulting

& +49 170 5867448 • @ denis@knaack.it •  $\ensuremath{\mathcal{O}}$  https://www.knaack.it

### **Profiles**

in /denisknaack

🔌 /dknaack

/knaackee

12/2021 - today

2000 - 2003

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

C#

NodeJS / Typescript

React / TypeScript

**Github Actions** 

Throughout my career, I have worked with various programming languages, tools, and services. My passion for technology motivated me to continually evolve. Customers appreciate my ability to integrate new technologies and provide solutions that often exceed their objectives.

With over 20 years in the field, my passion for technology and innovation has not diminished; it remains as strong as on my very first day.

# Professional Experience KNAACK.IT

Freelancing (C#, Node.JS, TypeScript, React, SQL) Steinberg am See, DE

Omniga GmbH & Co. KG 11/2012 – 02/2015
Software Development Professional (C# SOL JavaScript) Regensburg DF

Software Development Professional (C#, SQL, JavaScript)

Regensburg, DE

SmilingBits GmbH & Co. KG

Senior Manager Software Development (C#, SQL, JavaScript)

Regensburg, DE

SmilingBits GmbH & Co. KG 01/2008 - 04/2011

Manager Software Development (C#, SQL, JavaScript) Regensburg, DE

GoNamic GmbH 10/2003 – 01/2008

GoNamic GmbH 10/2003 – 01/2008 Manager Software Development (C#, SQL, JavaScript) Regensburg, DE

# Education BSZ Matthäus Runtinger BSIII

Fintech Startup

# Fachinformatiker Anwendungsentwicklung (IT Specialist in Application Development)

Freelance Projects (Excerpt)

### Development of backend solutions and APIs for a fintech st

Development of backend solutions and APIs for a fintech startup, utilizing C# and Microsoft SQL Database.

Automated Email Dispatch (Implementation of Automated Invoice Email Distribution)

Implementation of an automated system for emailing invoices, developed in

C#.
Visa Policy Update

Implementation of new requirements for visa payment processing using C#.

Website Relaunch C#

Redevelopment and modernization of a website using C#.

Transition from plain text passwords to hashed and salted passwords,

implemented in C#.

Mailgun Integration

### Consulting GraphQL

Implementation and documentation.

**Password Validation** 

GraphQL Backend

Plug-In System

Auto-Updater

Al Chatbot

TypeScript.

CI / CD

developed with React Native.

application, utilizing NodeJS.

Advising a development team on GraphQL implementation and best practices.

Development of a sample implementation for a GraphQL backend using NodeJS and TypeScript.

NNTP Client

Development of an NNTP client using C#.

Enhancement of a Windows client with a plug-in system, developed in C#.

Implementation of an automatic update system for a Windows application.

COVID Scanner App

React Native

Creation of an app for scanning and displaying information from QR codes,

Marketing Website React / TypeScript

TypeScript.

Development of a website for a mid-sized company, utilizing React and

Design and integration of an AI chatbot based on ChatGPT, implemented using React and TypeScript.

UI / UX

Figma

Creation and presentation of a user interface for a web application using

Figma.

Automatic Update Feature for Electron App

Development of a self-updating mechanism tailored for an Electron

GraphQL Backend NodeJS / TypeScript

Development of an API with integration to a PostgreSQL database, implemented using NodeJS and TypeScript.

Chrome Extension TypeScript

Development of a Chrome extension with ChatGPT integration, implemented in

Outlook Plugin TypeScript

Creation of a plugin for easier management of filters and folders in Outlook, developed in TypeScript.

Desktop Client NodeJS / Electron / TypeScript

Development of a cross-platform client for Windows, Mac, and Linux for

processing and analyzing AAF files, using NodeJS, Electron, TypeScript, and C#.

Creation and implementation of a Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) process for a team with various projects, utilizing GitHub

Actions.

Progressive Web App React / TypeScript

Progressive Web App

Recognition Web App (installable offline-read)

Development of a Progressive Web App (installable, offline-ready) with features including authentication, email sending, and more, built using React and TypeScript.